holmesglen.edu.au 2019-03-05

# Privacy Policy | Melbourne TAFE Courses & Degrees, Victoria

Holmesglen Institute respects your right to privacy and any personal information provided by you to the Institute will be held in confidence. This policy outlines how Holmesglen handles personal and health information in accordance with the Information Privacy Act 2000 (Vic.), Privacy Act 1988 (Cth) , the Health Records Act 2001 (Vic.) and the Higher Education Support Act (HESA) 2003 (Cth). The Policy applies to all personal and health information provided to Holmesglen Institute and information about individuals obtained from other sources.

Personal information collected by Holmesglen for the purposes of Commonwealth Supported Places or FEE-HELP/VET FEE-HELP assistance and the repayment of HELP loans is handled in accordance with the information privacy principles set out in the Information Privacy Act 2000 (Vic), Privacy Act 1988 (Cth) and the Higher Education Support Act (HESA) 2003 (Cth). Students who are eligible for Commonwealth Supported Places or FEE-HELP/VET FEE-HELP should refer to the Personal Information Procedure and Privacy Policy provided in your enrolment kit and/or available from the Information Office at any Holmesglen campus. 

### Collection of Information

We will only collect what information is necessary for us to provide an efficient and satisfactory service. We will advise you if we collect information relating to you from other sources. Your consent to use information for any other purpose will be requested. The Institute monitors and records details of all incoming electronic traffic to ensure the integrity of the Institute's networks. This information will be used for statistical analysis to help improve the services delivered by the Institute.

Some sections of the Holmesglen website use standard industry technologies such as 'cookies'. This anonymous information is used for statistical analysis to improve and develop the website and its services. Most internet browsers accept cookies. If you prefer not to receive them, you can adjust your browser settings. 

### Use of Disclosure

The information you have provided will primarily only be used for the service you have requested of us. We are obliged to pass on information to Government agencies when legally requested to, but in general, this is used only as a measure of Holmesglen's compliance, efficiency and effectiveness. 

### Data Quality

We endeavour at all times to ensure information held by the Institute about you is accurate and up to date. In fact, we encourage you to notify us of any inaccurate information so that it can be corrected. 

### Access and Correction

Students may review personal data held by us at any time by visiting the Holmesglen website or by contacting the Registrar's Department. Staff should contact the Personnel Department. All others who have provided the Institute with personal information should check with the appropriate area where that information was lodged. 

### Security of Data

At Holmesglen, we make every effort to see that personal data remains secure. Information or data is restricted to those who need to know and distribution of information is kept to a minimum. 

### Unique Identifiers

Holmesglen uses unique identifiers in its Student Administration and Staff Payroll Systems. These systems are designed to provide security of your information. Please advise us if you have concerns about your unique identifier. 

### Transborder Data Flow

Generally, we will not transfer personal information outside of Victoria without your consent. 

### Sensitive Information

We will not collect any sensitive information about you, except where directed for a specific purpose. Sensitive information is generally regarded as information relating to: 

  * Ethnic background
  * Religion
  * Political views
  * Sexual preference
  * Criminal records.

### Anonymity

Holmesglen respects everyone's right to anonymity, except in circumstances where it is necessary for you to provide us with your identity. 

### Openness

We are completely open with what we do with personal information and this is communicated by way of this Information Privacy Policy. 

### Breaches of this Policy

The Institute has an established Information Privacy Committee whose responsibilities include ensuring that details contained within this policy are adhered to throughout the Institute.

**In the first Instance, alleged breaches of this policy should be referred to the area where the information was initially lodged by you.  
If a satisfactory resolution cannot be reached at this level, the alleged breach should be submitted in writing to the Institute's Privacy Officer, P.O. Box 42, Holmesglen 3148.**
